It's so beautiful.
这棵树真漂亮
Hey!
喂
Don't cut it without my permission!
我不同意就不准剪
I'll sue you!
我会告你的
Sorry?
什么？
I will sue you!
我要告你
Don't do that!
不能剪
Hello.
你好
Good morning.
早上好
Can you look down?
你往楼下看？
I felt antsy and got here early.
我等不及就先跑来了
Hang on. I'll be right down.
等一下 我马上下去
Oh, stay there a bit longer.
你先待在上面
This situation with you on the balcony is like that, isn't it?
你在阳台上这种感觉很像那个吧？
Romeo and--
罗蜜欧与…
I'm coming down right now.
我马上下去
What a good girl.
真是个好女孩
KURUGA TOWN
（久瑠贺町）
Let me confirm.
我先确认一下
Mr. Yoshiyuki Shigeno, there's a large plum tree
重野义行先生家后面的邻居
growing out of your neighbor's house and
种的李子树枝叶会延伸到你家庭院
you've been distressed about the yearly outbreak of caterpillars.
每年都有大量毛毛虫 让你感到非常困扰
However, there was nothing you could do
不过你一直束手无策
because the house had been empty for years.
因为那间房子已空置多年
Then, a year ago, Ms. Masue Arimori moved into that house.
不过在一年前 有森万寿江女士搬进这间屋子
But nothing has been done about the plum tree
但也完全没有处理那棵李子树
and the caterpillars are manifesting again this year.
今年又有大量的毛毛虫肆虐
If possible, you'd like us to inform Ms. Arimori
你想要我们转告有森女士 如果可以的话
to fulfill her responsibility as an owner
请她善尽所有人的责任
and deal with the caterpillar problem.
采取措施解决毛毛虫问题
That's your request, yes?
这是你的委托内容 对吧？
That's right.
就是这样
We were drinking the other day and he said telling her directly could offend her.
之前我跟舅舅一起喝酒的时候 他说直接跟邻居说可能会冒犯对方
So I told him that I'll refer him to a lawyer.
我就说我可以介绍律师给你
Right.
对
I'm glad you came to us.
你能委托我们是对的
No matter how much it grows into your property,
就算枝叶伸进你家的范围内
it's illegal to cut them on your own.
擅自修剪是违法的
Mr. Haneoka here will suggest how you can deal with it.
羽根冈律师会提出建议的解决方案
Okay.
好
YOSHIYUKI SHIGENO'S HOUSE MASUE ARIMORI'S HOUSE
（重野义行住家 有森万寿江家）
You're right. There's loads of them.
确实 有好多毛毛虫
It's a larvae of a moth called fall webworm.
看起来是美国白蛾的幼虫
Don't show me. This is insect harassment.
不用给我看 这是昆虫骚扰
You don't have to look at it, but show motivation.
你不想看虫没关系 但至少要拿出一点干劲吧
But this case is so bland.
可是这个案件这么无聊
And most of all, the client seems so uninterested.
而且委托人根本就没有那个意思
I'm concerned about that too.
我也是对这一点感到很在意
It's probably that.
反正一定是这样吧
Mr. Shiozaki forced his uncle to make a case just to impress you.
盐崎先生想要让你有好印象 所以才强迫他委托我们的
What about me?
我怎么了？
Nothing.
没事
You don't look dependable.
你让我很担心
I asked her dad to take the case to begin with.
我原本是要麻烦他爸爸的
But he was too busy and it went to you.
是因为他太忙了 才换你来
You seem shallow.
你好像很轻浮
Please rest assured.
请放心
Despite his looks, Haneoka is as capable as the next guy.
别看他这样 我们的羽根冈…跟其他人一样能干
As the next guy?
抬举他了吧？
Exaggerating your capability could be seen as a lie.
过份夸大优秀会变成说谎 那才是问题吧
You should trust me.
你应该要信任我吧
Even so.
但是
Even so what?
但是什么？
Oh, a bug.
有虫
Coming.
来了
Good afternoon.
下午好
Therefore, Article 233 of the Civil Code
根据民法第233条
"Cutting off branches and roots of trees" stipulates that if your neighbor's
“树木枝叶与根部修剪”规定 土地所有者
tree branch grows over the boundary line into your yard,
在邻地树木枝叶越过两家的界线时
the landowner can ask the neighbor to cut off that branch.
可要求该树木所有人修剪树枝
Also, Article 717 of the Civil Co--
另外 民法第717条…
I understand.
了解
Then, could you take care of it?
那么 可以请你处理吗？
I apologize for the trouble.
抱歉给你们添麻烦了
No problem.
不会
I wonder if that was the right move. Didn't we pressure her a little too much?
你刚刚采取的方法真的好吗？ 会不会给她太大压力了？
It's fine.
没问题的
Is it really?
真的吗？
SATOMI COAST BUS
（里见海岸）
It won't be here for a long while.
车要好久才会来
The one we're getting on is there.
我们要搭的车在对面
I know.
我知道
See, I just thought I'd go to the beach--
看吧 我是想说 要不要就这样去海边…
You checked the timetable.
你刚刚明明就看了时间表
Maybe dip our feet in.
或许可以泡泡脚
-We're not here to have fun. -Come on. Until the bus comes.
-我们不是来玩的 -有什么关系 反正要等车
No. We could miss the…
不可以 要是没搭上车…
Man, it's so hot.
老天 也太热了吧
Ow, ow.
嗷…
Ouch.
哎哟
80 MILLION YEN IN DAMAGES FOR REAL ESTATE FRAUD
（不动产投资欺诈 受损总金额达八千万日圆）
My, that was an efficient job.
真是很有效率的工作
-We solved it in a second. -It wasn't a second.
-一秒就解决了 -才不是一秒
Do you know how many hours it took to--
你知道总共花了几小时…
It's just a figure of speech. Just say, "You're right."
这只是一种修辞 只想说：“你是对的”
-You're right. -Good.
-就是啊 -很好
Alright.
好了
I'm sorry to disturb you.
不好意思打扰你
Can I go to a job interview next Tuesday?
下星期二我可以去面试吗？
Yeah, sure. Is it going well?
可以 还顺利吗？
Yes. One of them went well and it's the final interview.
是 有一家公司好像还可以 要进行最后面试了
I see.
这样啊
I want you to get the job, but we're sure going to miss you.
我是希望你能找到工作 不过这样会很寂寞呢
Yes. You've been a great help.
就是啊 这阵子你帮了不少忙
Hello!
打扰了
We didn't order anything.
我们又没叫外卖 怎么了？
It's not that. My uncle's been sued by her neighbor!
不是啦 我舅舅说他被后面的邻居告了
What?
什么？
So, Ms. Masue Arimori has been troubled by the sounds of piano
也就是说 有森万寿江女士 在搬来的这一年内
coming from your house since the day she moved in.
因为重野先生家传来的钢琴声 而备受困扰
She's demanding an improvement of this situation
要求改善此状况 并以精神痛苦为由
and 500,000 yen in compensation for her emotional distress.
要求50万日圆的赔偿金
That's right.
对
This is only a content-certified mail, so you haven't been sued yet.
这只是存证信函 你还没有被告
It is under her name and she doesn't seem to have a lawyer.
以本人名义寄出 看起来她并没有请律师
However, we shouldn't let our guard down.
不过也不能掉以轻心
Have you ever had complaints about the piano?
你之前有收到 任何关于钢琴声的抱怨吗？
No.
没有
Have you had any trouble with Ms. Arimori in the past?
还是你跟有森女士 之前有其他的纠纷？
None at all.
完全没有
You've met her, yes?
你们认识吧？
We've said hi.
只是打过招呼而已
Do you play the piano often?
你常常弹钢琴吗？
Sometimes.
偶尔会弹
Since my mother passed away, I've had nothing to do.
我母亲过世后 我无事可做
So I bought it.
就买了钢琴
Around what time?
大概哪个时段？
I play between noon and seven p.m.
我弹琴的时间大概从中午到晚上七点
I wear headphones when I play outside that time.
其他时段我会戴耳机
If that's the case, it is unlikely for the court to accept her claim.
如果情况属实 法院应该不会同意她的请求
You could lose if you're playing at ridiculous times and volumes
如果弹琴的时间和音量超过一般认知
and if you don't stop even after repeated warnings.
而且经多次提醒仍不改正 确实有可能败诉
But this is not the case.
不过你的情况并非如此
Okay.
好
I guess it's probably a counterpunch to the insect complaint.
可能是因为你抱怨毛虫的事 她想进行反击吧
Maybe we were too tough on Ms. Arimori, after all.
果然给有森女士太大压力了
I thought you'd be pleased. We're getting another consultation fee.
你不是应该要开心吗？ 又可以拿到一笔咨询费了
But if I think about their relationship as neighbors…
可是一想到他们是邻居关系…
Hey.
嘿
Yes?
怎么了？
You stay off this case.
你就不要管了
I'll ask Oba to help me from now on.
之后的调查我会请大庭帮忙
What are you talking about? I need to keep an eye on you.
你在说什么？ 我得盯着你 不让你惹出麻烦…
No, I'm serious.
我是说真的
Aren't you stepping over boundaries?
这样不会太过吧？
You're a paralegal. I need you to follow my policies.
你是律师助理 要听从我的方针才对
I'm sorry.
对不起
Go do some accounting at the office.
你就留在律所里算账吧
Okay.
好
Why don't you two go home? How long are you going to stay?
怎么还不回家？你们是要待多久啦？
But they're not back yet.
可是他们还没回来
It's so late.
已经这么晚了
Is there a chance they're not coming back today?
该不会他们今天回不来了吧？
They will.
会回来啦
What if they missed the hourly bus
要是他们错过了 一小时只有一班的公交车
and have no choice but to stay the night?
也就只能留下来过夜了吧？
And what if there's only one room available?!
然后 旅馆只剩下一个房间
What?
什么？
You see it in TV dramas, right?
电视剧里不是都这样演的吗？
They decide to stay and there's only one room left.
想要留下来过夜 结果只剩下一个房间
And they end up in the same room, saying "Don't come into my side…"
不得已只好睡同一个房间 说着“不要超过这条线”
but they start to get cozy. You know?!
但两人之间越走越近 知道吧？
Y-You're overthinking it.
你想太多了
Aren't you worried, dad?
你不会担心吗 爸爸？
Don't call me dad.
不要叫我爸爸
Why not?
为什么？
But that won't happen.
不可能发生这种事
They're both young man and woman. You never know.
一对年轻男女 谁也说不准
We're back.
我们回来了
-Welcome back! -Welcome!
-欢迎回来
Welcome home.
回来啦
We're back.
我们回来了
Haneo.
羽男
Hm?
嗯？
The other day, you asked me how I feel about Ishiko.
你先前问过我对石子学姐是怎么样的
Yeah.
是
I like Ishiko.
我…喜欢石子学姐
I see.
这样啊
And why are you telling me this?
为什么要告诉我？
If I ask her out, things might get awkward regardless of if it goes well or not.
我告白之后 无论结果好坏 要是气氛变尴尬了好像不太好
So, you're gonna ask her out officially?
所以你要正式告白？
I intend to.
我是这么打算的
But when? When is this happening?
什么时候？你什么时候要说？
Um, I still haven't…
那个我…
Haven't decided?
还没决定？
Right.
对
Okay, I see. Let me know when you've asked her.
我知道了 那你告白了再跟我说
If that's the case, however it may turn out,
这样的话 不管结果如何
when I've told her I'll…
告白了之后 我就…
I'll touch my nose.
摸摸鼻子当做暗号
Got it. Hey, are you coming in tomorrow?
好 我知道了 你明天会来上班吗？
Um, yes.
会
Then could you investigate Mr. Shigeno's case?
那么重野先生的案子 可以麻烦你去打听消息吗？
I don't mind.
可以
I asked Ishiko to do some paperwork.
我已经石子小姐处理一些文书工作了
Right.
好
Okay. See you tomorrow.
好 那明天见
Ears, yeah?
耳朵 对吧？
-The nose! -Right, the nose.
-是鼻子 -鼻子啊
See you.
回见
Yup. It's the next right.
接下来右转
Okay.
好
Did something happen between you and Haneo?
你跟羽男先生发生了什么事吗？
He asked for my help out of the blue.
因为他突然叫我来做这件事
To be honest, I'm not sure.
老实说我也不知道
Huh? Was it really okay for you to come?
咦？那你跑来真的没问题吗？
Yes. I've finished processing the expenses.
是 我已经算完帐了
And since we're getting paid, I'll do what I can.
我是领工资的 能做的事情要尽量做
Ms. Arimori is stylish and pretty, isn't she?
有森女士很时髦 也很美吧？
She's become the "it girl" of the neighborhood association, right?
她搬来之后就成为镇民会的女神了
-And she has a lot of hobbies. -She's well educated.
-而且她兴趣广泛 -还很博学
She knows a lot about classical music, paintings and movies.
古典乐、绘画 连电影都有涉猎
The other day, she told me about the news where the fast movie's culprit
先前那个快电影的犯人被逮捕的新闻
was arrested in detail.
也是她详细解释给我听的
Now, President of the Association.
我想先请教镇民会长
How would you describe Mr. Shigeno?
重野先生是什么样的人？
I barely know anything about him.
我几乎不了解他
He doesn't come to the gatherings either, so I'm not sure.
聚会时也不会出现 所以我并不清楚
Right, Ms. Hashimoto?
对吧 桥本女士？
Right. I don't think he has any close friends.
应该没有人跟他很熟吧？
Not even one?
一个也没有吗？
He's the complete opposite of Ms. Arimori.
他跟有森女士是完全相反的类型
There are many elderly people living here.
这附近住了好多老人家
Seems the generation who moved here when it was developed as a bedroom community
好像是当初开发为通勤住宅区时 住在这里的那代人
has aged out.
高龄化的关系
Ishiko?
学姐？
-I'm fine. Really. -Let's go to hospital.
-我没事 -我们去医院吧
No!
一定要
I'll carry your stuff.
我来帮你拿东西
Okay.
好
Get on!
上来吧！
But…
可是…
We can't get a taxi here. Just up to the main road.
这里打不到车 我背你到大马路
Thank you.
那就麻烦你了
Sure.
好
It could be an ovarian cyst.
可能是卵巢囊肿
Let's do the tumor marker test today.
今天先做肿瘤标记检查吧
I'll write a referral letter to a hospital in Tokyo,
我会写转诊单给东京的医院
so please do the MRI test there.
请你到那边做核磁共振
How was it?
怎么样？
She said I was under the air conditioner too much.
医生说我吹太多冷气了
I'm sorry I made you worry.
让你担心了 不好意思
Not at all. I'm just glad.
不会 没事就好
Thanks.
是
Get in.
请上车
I called Ms. Hashimoto and borrowed her car.
我打电话给桥本女士 跟她借了车
For me?
为了我吗？
Yes.
是的
Are those for me too?
那该不会也是要给我的？
Yes. I bought both stick-on and non-stick heat packs.
对 手握式和黏贴式 两种热敷包我都买了
I appreciate it.
太谢谢了
You made me very happy.
我很高兴
No worries. Please get in.
别客气 请上车
Okay, I'm gonna go return the car.
那我赶快去还车
Thank you very much.
太感谢了
No problem.
不会
Take a good rest during the weekend.
周末请好好休息
Thanks. Please drive safely.
谢谢 请小心开车
I will.
好
I'm home.
我回来了
-Dad. -Huh?
-爸爸 -嗯？
Sleep on your bed.
去床上睡吧
Welcome home.
回来啦
Yeah, thanks.
对 谢谢
You've worked hard today.
今天也辛苦了
Here. A souvenir.
给 纪念品
You two really are partners.
果然是伙伴
See, Haneo brought this just now.
你看 刚刚羽男也拿给我
His souvenir.
他的纪念品
You two are getting in sync, huh?
你俩越来越有默契了 对吧？
You're a paralegal. I need you to follow my policies.
你是律师助理 要听从我的方针才对
Go do some accounting at the office.
你就留在律所里算账吧
I wonder.
我很怀疑
Seriously, don't push yourself.
真的不要太过勉强
I slept the whole weekend, so I'm fine.
我周末睡很饱 没问题的
Alright. Shall we start from Mr. Shigeno's house today?
今天先到重野先生家去看看吧
Yes.
好
We borrowed a noise meter--
噪音计也借到了…
Huh? Haneo!
嗯？羽男先生
-No. -Hey.
-不要 -嘿
Why are you here?
你为什么会在这里？
I'm helping Mr. Oba.
我来帮大庭先生
Hmm.
嗯
Oh, I asked her.
是我请她来的
No, I did.
不 是我拜托他的
It doesn't matter which.
是谁都不要紧
What are you doing?
你来做什么？
Right. I did a little research and
对 我做了点研究
I found out there's an outbreak of fall webworm in the entire Kuruga town.
确认美国白蛾在整个久瑠贺町大爆发
It's actually a problem in the whole prefecture now.
事实上 这已经是全县的问题了
And if each town's community wants to exterminate it,
各地自治会如果想要消灭害虫
the prefecture lends out this pest control equipment.
县府可以出借害虫防治设备
This is the equipment?
就是这个吗？
Yup.
对
I'm surprised you found that out. You're afraid of bugs.
你不是怕虫吗？还调查了这么多东西
I squinted my eyes.
我眯着眼睛看
Oh, here it comes!
出来了
It's an environmentally friendly naturally derived pesticide.
这是环保型驱虫剂 用天然材料制成的
So it won't affect the surrounding environment.
所以不会影响周遭的环境
You're a lifesaver. The caterpillars are everywhere.
真是帮了大忙 到处都是毛毛虫
I was so sick of them.
实在是受够了
I spoke with the president and
我跟会长谈过了
the neighbor's association will be handling the caterpillars from now on.
今后每年的毛毛虫驱除作业 就由镇民会来处理
That's right.
没错
So, from now on, you won't have to deal with the plum tree personally.
所以有森女士今后就不用 自己处理李子树的问题了
Thank you.
太好了
Mr. Shigeno said as long as the insects are gone,
重野先生也说了 只要没有毛毛虫
he's not bothered by the branches.
就不介意枝叶的问题
If we get rid of the insects, we can tell her
既然驱除了毛毛虫 剩下的树枝就不是问题了
we no longer care about the branches as an exchange condition.
我们不在意了 只要提出这样的交换条件
Do you think she'll withdraw the noise problem now?
她应该就会撤销噪音的案子了吧？
Most likely.
应该会
So, that's your plan.
你们是这么打算的
Getting rid of the insects has nothing to do with the noise problem.
不管有没有驱虫 跟噪音问题都是两码事
Huh? Oh, sorry. We're having a private conversation.
不好意思 这是我们私底下的谈话
I've been entrusted to deal with this case.
她委托我处理这个案子
What?
什么？
I was a judicial scrivener.
我以前是司法书士
I advised her to send the content-certified mail.
是我建议她寄出存证信函的
Let's talk about the contents with me.
详情请跟我谈吧
But you're not her official repres--
但你不是正式的代理律师吧…
I'm not doing this as a profession.
我没有把这个当成职业
Well, since we're in the same neighborhood association,
因为参加了镇民会 她请我居中协调
she personally asked me to intervene.
是个人的委托
Is that true?
是这样吗？
You're so persistent.
真固执
She doesn't want to talk to you directly anymore.
她不想再跟你们直接讲话了
So, where should we start?
要从哪里开始谈呢？
Regarding the noise, we'll do more to keep it down.
关于噪音的问题 我们会更努力改善
And the compensation?
赔偿金呢？
I'm sorry to say this, but I don't think it's a reasonable amount.
非常抱歉 但我们认为那不是合理的金额
That's not for you to decide, is it?
合不合理不是由你来决定吧？
From now on, make sure everything goes through me.
今后所有的联络都请通过我
It was him?
他这么说吗？
Right.
对
He's not her official representative, so we don't have to go through him.
会长并不是正式的代理律师 我们不一定要通过他
But if Ms. Arimori herself has no intention of talking to us directly…
但如果有森女士 无意要直接跟我们谈的话…
You don't have any association with the president, right?
你跟镇民会长没有任何交流吧？
I've only greeted him once.
只有打过一次招呼
We'll negotiate one more--
我们再交涉一次看看…
It's fine.
不用了
I'll pay the full amount.
我会支付全额
I'm the one who made things complicated by involving a lawyer.
都怪我请律师介入 才会把事情搞得这么复杂
I see.
原来如此
If that's the case…
这样的话…
Mr. Shigeno.
重野先生
Yes?
怎么了？
In truth,
其实
aren't you and Ms. Arimori good friends?
你跟有森女士的关系很好吧？
Over there.
那边
H-Hey.
等一下
You have a movie ticket framed.
你把一张电影票裱框起来
Hey.
喂
It was screened at a revival house and it's from January this year.
那是在复兴剧院上映时的票 日期是今年一月
And the same ticket…
而在有森女士家
was also displayed in Ms. Arimori's house.
她也把同一张电影票裱框起来
I wondered if you two watched the movie together.
我在想你们是不是 一起去看了这部电影
I apologize if I'm wrong.
如果猜错了 我很抱歉
You're right.
没错
Since she moved in a year ago,
她在一年前搬来之后
she was the only person in the neighborhood
常常会分享东西给我
who shared things with me and she became someone I could talk to.
是我唯一聊得来的邻居
She's invited me to watch a movie together.
她邀我一起去看电影
But gradually, we kind of drifted apart
不过后来我们渐渐疏远了
and I haven't seen her for the past few months.
我已经好几个月没见到她了
I'll pay the compensation.
我会付赔偿金
It's okay now.
不用再麻烦你们了
Excuse me.
请问
May I use your bathroom?
可以借个洗手间吗？
Sure, it's down the hallway on your right.
请 走廊出去右边就是了
Thank you.
谢谢
Oh, my leg…
脚好麻…
My right leg…
右脚好麻…
I wonder if Ms. Arimori came to dislike Mr. Shigeno for some reason
有森女士好像是因为某些原因 讨厌重野先生
and decided to sue him.
才决定要告他的
It's too soon to decide.
现在要判断还太早
But Mr. Shigeno just seemed so sad.
不过重野先生好像很伤心
He hired a lawyer to avoid a dispute, but it got worse instead.
他请律师原本是要避免冲突 结果情况反而变更糟
Okay, that's enough. No need to think further.
不要再想了
-The client said it's fine. -But he doesn't have to pay--
-委托人都说没事了 -但他没必要付赔偿金…
You two stay put.
你俩都不要再插手了
Excuse me?
什么？
I told you, right?
我说过了吧？
Follow my policies.
要听从我的方针
Geez.
受不了
I'm sorry about the sudden invitation. I wanted to sit and talk with you.
不好意思 突然约你出来 我想要好好跟你聊聊
I'm happy you asked me.
我很高兴
You're drinking jasmine tea.
你喝茉莉花茶
So, you don't drink alcohol?
是不能喝酒吗？
I love it, but I have a check-up tomorrow.
我很喜欢喝 但明天要去做检查
What? Medical exam?
什么？健康检查吗？
-Yes. -We should cut this short.
-是的 -那我们早点结束吧
-Oh, it's fine. -You know…
-没关系 -你知道…
I didn't worry about things like that before.
我以前完全不在意这种事的
But these days, I'm afraid of finding out the results.
但最近很怕看结果
Doesn't it freak you out just seeing the word "retest"?
看到“复查”两字 不觉得会很紧张吗？
You start imagining the worst-case scenario.
都会开始相像最糟的情况
It could be an ovarian cyst.
可能是卵巢囊肿
Let's do the tumor marker test today.
今天先做肿瘤标记检查吧
It does make you think about things, doesn't it?
真的是会想很多吧？
Yeah.
是啊
If I'm gone, my father will be alone.
如果我走了 就只剩下我爸了
It's embarrassing, but he's sloppy with money.
挺难为情的 他在钱财方面很粗心
So, I'd have to summarize the office finances into--
我得把律所的资金管理情况 写在笔记本上面才行…
Hang on. It's only a medical exam. You're overthinking it.
等一下…只不过是健康检查 你也想太多了吧
-You're right. -Yeah.
-说得也是 -就是说啊
-Please excuse me. -You scared me.
-真不好意思 -吓到我了
It's fine.
不会
-Ma'am. -Woah, hang on a sec.
-女士 -等一下
Are you gonna keep calling me "ma'am"?
确认一下 你以后都要叫我“女士”吗？
I'm just making sure.
我只是确认一下
Yes.
对
Here you go.
菜来啦
Thank you.
谢谢
-This is good. -Thank you very much.
-这很好吃 -谢谢
Let me. Oh, well.
我来
And?
然后呢？
It's about your brother.
关于你弟弟的事
Oh, no. Did he do something?
不会吧？他做什么了吗？
Like he's too insensitive and driving you crazy?
还是他太木了 你受不了？
It's nothing like that.
不是的
We always investigated together, but recently, he tries to work alone.
我们以前都是一起调查 但他最近都想单独行动
Even when I ask him about it, his answers don't seem honest.
问他原因 他好像没有老实回答
You know what? You should ask him what you want to know.
知道吗？你有想知道的事情 就直接去问他
No one knows what he's thinking.
没有人知道他在想什么
She nags a lot, so it must be tiring. I've been there.
她很唠叨 你一定很累 辛苦了
Well, I can't deny that.
这我无法否认
-Oh, I've had enough. -You sure?
-我不能再喝了 -是吗？
I've become such a lightweight now.
我酒量越来越差了
It makes me feel so old.
感觉年纪大了
I may not have much time left.
我可能时日无多了
"Oh, come on. That's not true."
“不…才不是这样”
Can you not say things where I'm expected to respond like that?
这不是摆明了要我这么说 请不要这样
But seriously. I've become really forgetful.
说真的 我越来越健忘了
If Shoko hadn't come back,
硝子没有回来的话
I probably would've retired by now.
我可能早就退休了
Come back?
回来？
Yeah. I got divorced when she entered junior high school.
她上高中的时候 我跟她妈妈离婚了
We've lived apart since then.
之后都一直分隔两地
And we started living together again three years ago.
三年前 她搬回来跟我一起住
I see.
原来如此
But we still have this emotional distance, you know?
不过感觉还是很有距离
She wasn't so polite towards me before.
她以前不会对我说敬语
And how's work? Are you two getting along?
工作呢？两人合作还顺利吗？
Well, yeah. As usual.
对 一般吧
-Yes. -I see.
-对 -原来如此
He's really staring.
他真的是盯着看
He's looking at me, right?
他是在看我吧？
Yeah, he is.
对 是看你
So intense.
压力好大
TEICHI UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
（帝智大学医学系附属医院）
I'M COMING IN AT 11 TODAY. SORRY FOR THE INCONVENIENCE. SHOKO ISHIDA
（今天11点才会进办公室 不好意思添麻烦了 石田硝子）
Good morning.
早上好
Morning.
早
I'm off.
那我走了
Where to?
去哪里？
Informing the association president know that we're paying.
去跟镇民会长报告支付赔偿金的事
I'm coming with you.
我也要去
Like I said--
我之前就说…
Why are you trying to proceed with this on your own?
你为什么要自己一个人进行？
You value efficiency. And yet, why?
明明是很重视效率的人 为什么？
Rather than working on your own, shouldn't you make use of me, a paralegal?
与其独自行动 好好利用 我这个律师助理不是更好吗？
I'm sorry for always butting in.
很抱歉我总是提意见
As the one in charge of this firm,
但身为律所的管理者
I'll continue to question your behavior if I think it'll cause trouble.
对于可能造成问题的行为 我之后还是会继续提出意见
And I believe my suggestions are necessary
为了从不同角度检视案件
in order to examine the case from various angles.
我也相信我的提案是必须的
But those are only
但这些都只是
my personal opinions
我的个人意见
and I will follow the final decision you make.
最后怎么决定 我会听从你的判断
So, please let me stay by your side
所以 请让我以伙伴的身份
as your partner.
待在你身边
No!
不要
You stay here.
你留在这里
Please wait. I don't understand!
请等一下 我不明白
-Stay here. -Why won't you let me…
-你留在这里 -你为什么就不让我…
You're unwell, right?
你身体不舒服吧？
For the past few days,
这几天
you've been looking pale.
你气色都很差
And you were rubbing your stomach, so I wanted you to take it easy.
一直在揉肚子 我想着不要让你太劳累
Even if I tell you to rest, you won't listen. Right?
但是叫你休息 你也不会听吧？
That's why…
所以…
I went for a check-up this morning.
我今天早上去检查了
They think it's a benign tumor.
医生认为是良性肿瘤
If I get treated, there's no problem.
只要接受治疗 就不会有问题
Really?
真的吗？
I appreciate your kindness.
谢谢你的好意
You've changed a little.
你有点不一样了
Huh? Oh, you mean my hair and my clothes?
什么？你是说发型和衣服吗？
I just thought this was more comfortable.
我只是觉得这样比较轻松
Yes. I think it's nice.
对 我觉得很不错
So, can I come with you?
那我可以跟你去吗？
Sure.
好啊
Aren't you going to reject the compensation?
赔偿金的事不再继续争取吗？
Yeah, I--
对 我是…
I think we should continue to negotiate.
我认为应该要继续交涉
500,000 yen for that case is just unreasonable.
这个案子求偿50万日圆并不合理
Going to court is an option, but there's the neighborhood relationship issue.
刻意上法院也是一个办法 但邻居关系也要考量进去
Above all, it'll take up a lot of money and time.
更重要的是 这样很花时间和金钱
So it may not be the best option for Mr. Shigeno.
对重野先生来说可能不是最好的办法
For this case, I think the cause of the dispute--
果然还是要找出争执的根本原因…
Stop, stop.
停
Now that you're well, you're a pain.
你这么有精神也是很麻烦
Fine.
好吧
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Thank you.
谢谢
Mr. Ao Oba, please enter.
大庭苍生先生 请进
Yes.
好
FINAL INTERVIEW VENUE
（最终面试会场）
Hello.
你好
Please come in.
请进
Mr. Mikogami is here.
御子神先生到了
-Good morning.
-早上好
Yes?
是谁？
We're sorry to come to you directly.
很抱歉 跳过会长直接来找你
Could we talk to you one more time?
可以再跟你谈谈吗？
We were wondering
我们不知道
if that content-certified mail is what you really wished for.
那封存证信函是否真是你的意思
When I met the president,
我跟会长见面时
I let it slip that I had been warned by a lawyer.
不小心说出律师警告的事情
And then,
结果
he told me he'll take action to restrain you.
他就说要出手反制对方
Is that why the piano issue came up?
钢琴的问题是这样才出现的？
I told him I overheard the piano once. And it turned into a big deal.
我告诉他我曾经听过一次 没想到会闹得这么大
The compensation was also his idea?
赔偿金也是会长提出来的？
I left everything to him, so I didn't know about it.
我全部都交给他处理 所以也不是很清楚
I feel terrible towards Mr. Shigeno.
总觉得对重野先生很过意不去
Then, that content-certified mail…
那么 那封存证信函…
Oh, please let me withdraw it.
请让我把它撤销
I'll speak to the president myself.
我也会去跟会长说的
Then, can I get your signature for confirmation? Just in case.
那么 可以请你签个名吗？以防万一
Sure.
好
Let's see.
我找找看
You must've been surprised too. For us to suddenly show up like that.
有森女士 你一定吓一跳吧 我们就这样突然跑来
Actually, didn't you want him to tell you directly
其实 你希望重野先生不要通过律师
instead of hiring a lawyer?
直接来找你谈吧？
Yes.
对
Mr. Shigeno said that you two have been to the movies together.
重野先生说你们一起去看过电影
At one point, we used to see each other often.
有一阵子 我们常常碰面
But if I think about it, he's never asked me out.
不过仔细想想 他从来没有约过我
I guess it was my one-sided love.
看来只是我单相思吧
-Huh? -What?
-咦？ -什么？
You're the one with feelings for…
都是有森女士提出邀约吗？
Your surprise is rude to Mr. Shigeno.
你这么讶异 对重野先生太失礼了
But you were surprised too.
你刚刚也很惊讶啊
Sorry.
不好意思
Everyone asked me why I decided to move here.
大家都问我为什么会搬来这里
But he never asked me anything.
只有他从来没问过我
Right.
是
That kind of silent kindness just felt comfortable.
这种什么都不说出口的体贴 让我很安心
Were you two dating?
两位在交往吗？
No, it wasn't like that.
不 没有进展到那一步
Though, he's mentioned that he wants to celebrate my birthday with me.
不过 他说过等我生日时 想要跟我一起庆祝
But about three months ago,
不过在大概三个月前
all of a sudden,
很突然地
he said he wants to cancel our meeting.
他说想要取消约定
And that we shouldn't see each other anymore.
以后也不要再碰面了
That was it.
我们就断了联系
Do you have any idea why?
是有什么原因吗？
None at all.
我完全想不到
-Huh? -Oh.
-嗯？ -哦
Hello.
辛苦了
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
What's wrong?
怎么了吗？
Oh, I wanted to speak to Ishiko.
我有点事想跟石子学姐说
Huh?
什么？
Oh, right. See ya, then.
好 那我先走了
I'll get my bike and go home.
我去骑自行车回家
-Um… -See you tomorrow.
-啊… -明天交
See you.
回见
And?
什么事？
Today's interview went well.
今天的面试感觉很有机会
Oh, that's great!
真是太好了
Yes. And…
是 等…
And…
等…
And when I get the job,
等我确定找到工作
I'm going to ask you out.
就会向石子学姐告白
What?
什么？
I won't now because we work together and that'll be against the rules.
我还在律所的时候算是违反原则 所以现在还不会告白
Um, how should I put it…
该怎么说呢…
So, this is like a confession about a confession?
你说的告白是那个告白吗？
Oh…
啊…
I guess so.
就是这样
See you tomorrow!
明天见
Wha…
怎…
KURUGA TOWN KONJAC SHORTBREAD
（久瑠贺町魔芋酥饼）
Shortbread?
这是魔芋酥饼
Thank you.
谢谢
Here.
请用
I wonder why Mr. Shigeno stopped seeing her.
到底是什么呢？ 重野先生不再跟她见面的理由
Doesn't matter now, does it? The case is closed.
是什么不要紧 对吧？ 案子已经结束了
Do we need to be hired to help?
没请我们就不能帮忙吗？
Mr. Shigeno definitely has feelings for Ms. Arimori, don't you think?
重野先生一定是 对有森女士有意思的吧？
If they like each other, shouldn't we do something?
明明就是两情相悦 这样下去真的好吗？
I think I passed the interview.
我的面试应该会通过
So, I think this will be the last case I'll be working on.
所以这会是我参与的最后一个案子了
I want to be of help to the client.
我想要帮委托人的忙
Didn't you just jinx it?
你刚刚是不是做了预告？
What?
什么？
It won't be funny if you fail.
要是面试没通过就不好玩了
I'll be fine.
没问题的
So?
怎么办？
Since we've already been paid, it's not against my rules to serve the client.
我们都拿钱了 为委托人尽心尽力并不违反我的原则
You heard her.
你听到了
Now, let's find out why they stopped seeing each other.
我们就来找出他们不再见面的理由吧
While we drink some tea.
我去泡茶
Thank you.
谢谢
You did?
你说了吗？
Huh?
什么？
You touched your nose. Was that the sign?
刚刚的手势是那个意思吗？
Sign?
哪个意思？
You know, if you ask Ishiko…
你懂的 你要对石子小姐…
Oh, it was just itchy.
只是鼻子有点痒
No need to hide it!
不用隐瞒啦
I'm not.
我没有隐瞒
Fine, if you say so.
你坚持的话 那就这样吧
-Seriously, I haven't! -What?
-真的没有 -什么？
But I guess you're not completely wrong.
好像也不能说没有
What does that mean?! Which is it? Which?
这什么意味深长的话？ 到底说了没有？是哪个…
-Well… -Tell me.
-那个… -告诉我啊
What's this about?
你们在聊什么？
You said, "Which?"
你说了“哪个”
We were wondering which is faster, the semi-express train or the rapid train.
我们在聊“准急”和“快速” 哪个比较快
Why that topic now?
为什么现在要聊这个？
Thanks for the tea.
谢谢你的茶
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Hey!
喂！
You got some on me.
搞什么 都喷到我了
-This is… -Isn't it too bitter?
-这实在… -也太苦了吧？
This is the green tea my dad bought. It has high catechin content.
这是我爸买的绿茶 我选了儿茶素含量比较高的
It tastes healthy, but it has a kick.
喝起来感觉对身体是好的 但味道真的很苦
Something wrong?
怎么了？
Was that nutrient content?
那是营养成分吗？
May I use your bathroom?
可以用下洗手间吗？
My leg. My right leg.
脚好麻 右脚好麻
One banana, 468.
一根香蕉 468
A pack of natto, 330.
一包纳豆 330
Pork fillet, 492.
猪里脊 492
Half an avocado, 648.
半颗牛油果 648
Two taros, 768.
两个芋头 768
Potato was…
土豆…
Pumpkin, 630.
南瓜 630
Hello.
你好
Excuse us for coming. You weren't at home.
不好意思就这样跑来 你没在家
Oh, it's already time for our appointment. I'm sorry.
我们约见面的时间到了 不好意思
Um, before we submit the report,
那个…在我们提出报告之前
may I ask you one question?
可以请教你一件事吗？
Please forgive me for stepping into your personal life.
介入你的私生活 还请见谅
If it's uncalled for, we'll leave immediately.
如果不希望我们多管闲事 我们也会马上离开
What is it?
什么事？
Mr. Shigeno, are you ill?
重野先生 你是不是生病了？
There was a vegetable chart on your refrigerator.
你家冰箱上贴了一张蔬菜表
That's for potassium content, isn't it?
上面标示了钾含量吧？
And on your calendar, the word "Tsuru" was written
另外在日历上 每周有三天
three times a week.
写了“鹤”字
Could that be about
那该不会
Tsuruyama Hospital?
就是指鹤山医院吧？
So, we thought maybe…
所以我们以为…
Well. Actually, I uh…
其实我患上了…
I'm on dialysis for chronic kidney disease.
慢性肾衰竭 目前在做透析
That's why I'm watching my potassium intake.
会注意钾含量也是因为这件事
And the reason you stopped seeing Ms. Arimori is also…
你说不会再跟有森女士见面也是…
Yeah. Because I'll just be causing her trouble.
对 因为只会给她添麻烦
Even if
即使
by chance
有机会
we became close,
我们的关系变得更亲密了
I don't have long to live.
我也时日无多了吧
If I think about the procedures after my death and what she has to bear,
想到我死后 还要让她办手续 负担一些事
it's better to be alone…
不如自己一个人还比较好…
If you'd like, there are things we can help you with.
如果你愿意的话 这些事情我们可以帮忙
We can assist in making a will and disposing of unwanted items
在身体还健康 有正确判断力的时候
to determine the division of property
协助拟定遗嘱 决定财产分配
while you're healthy and able to make accurate decisions.
以及处理不需要的东西 这些我们都可以帮忙
We may not be able to erase your worries,
或许没办法完全消除你的不安
but we could help you reduce it.
但应该可以减轻一些吧
Right.
好
Then, you and Ms. Arimori--
这样一来就可以跟有森女士…
But you know…
但是呢…
It's embarrassing for the elderly to fall in love.
一把年纪还谈恋爱 有点尴尬吧
You should tell the person you love how you feel.
喜欢一个人 就应该要好好说出来
Age doesn't matter.
跟几岁没有什么关系
I also want you to enjoy your life no matter how old you become.
我也希望 你不管到几岁都能好好享受人生
Young people are often told to have dreams for the future.
大家常说 年轻人要对未来抱持梦想
But the elderly people are the young people's future itself.
但老人家就是年轻人的未来啊
I think it's the elderly's duty to enjoy their life.
一把年纪也有义务享受生活
Or something.
诸如此类的
Well, but…
可是…
Come to think of it, today, September 8th is
想一想吧 今天是9月8日
Ms. Arimori's birthday. Isn't it?
是有森女士的生日吧？
There was a schedule written on the calendar at your house too.
重野先生家的日历上写了预定的行程
If that has to do with her birthday,
如果是为了帮她庆生
Ms. Arimori said she has no plans for today yet.
有森女士说她今天还没有安排
I'd like your help
那就麻烦你们了
with the arrangements of my estate.
帮我安排财产
Sure.
好
Yes?
是谁？
I wonder what he wrote on his calendar.
日历上写的预定行程是什么呢？
Yeah, we couldn't ask.
不知道
Apparently, he made a reservation at Vivace, a restaurant with a piano.
他在一家叫微瓦斯的餐厅预订了位置 里面有钢琴
What?
什么？
He told me earlier.
我刚刚问他的
Hang on a sec. He's gonna play the piano?
等一下 他要在餐厅里弹钢琴？
I heard that Ms. Arimori likes this scene
有森女士 好像很喜欢《卡萨布兰卡》里
from Casablanca, where the character asks the pianist to play "As Time Goes By."
请钢琴师弹《时光飞逝》那一幕
That's why he was practicing.
所以他才在练琴啊
I received the email.
我收到信了
From that interview.
是我去面试的公司
-Ooh! -Can I open it?
-哦！ -我可以打开吗？
-Of course. Open it. -Right.
-当然 请看 -好
Here goes.
我要看了
You got this.
你可以的
I got the job!
我拿下这份工作了
-Congratulations. -Thank you.
-恭喜 -谢谢
It's a new beginning.
踏出全新的一步了
Yes.
是的
INCREASE IN NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO DOES DEATH CLEANING
（进行“生前整理”的人越来越多）
MANY PEOPLE ARRANGE THEIR END OF LIFE PLANNING
（很多人会安排“临终活动”）
This is from my uncle.
这是我舅舅要送你们的
Thank you.
谢谢
I see you in a whole new light, Haneo.
我对你刮目相看了 羽男
I wouldn't mind leaving Shoko
如果是你 就能放心
in your care.
把硝子交给你了
Huh?
什么？
She's a nice girl.
她是个好姑娘
So I was looking out to make sure she doesn't end up with a weirdo.
我一直在守护她 确定她不会跟奇怪的人交往
But,
不过
if it's you…
如果是你的话…
Um, could you stop with your wild imagination?
可以请你不要胡乱妄想吗？
She's just a partner to me.
她对我来说就只是搭档
He's not listening.
他没在听
Can I talk to you after work tomorrow?
明天下班后 可以跟你谈谈吗？
Ouch.
哎哟
Good evening.
晚上好
I'm sorry, you must be tired.
不好意思 你一定很累了
No, I'm fine.
不会
Nakamaru, the company that hired me
录取我的中丸公司
is a company that mainly sells office supplies.
是以售卖办公室用品为主的企业
It's a completely different type of job, but I was attracted to their energy.
虽然是不同的工作类型 不过公司很有活力 我受到吸引了
Sounds like a job interview.
好像在面试一样
I will ask you out as I declared.
我要照先前的宣言 向你告白
Please go out with me.
请跟我交往
"It's a haunted apartment."
“那间公寓闹鬼”
If I had known, I wouldn't have rented it.
早知道是这种房子 我绝对不会租
You had the obligation to notify that someone had died--
有人在房子里过世 应该有义务要告知租户吧…
Why don't you tell the court it's a breach of contract because it's haunted?
你为何不告诉法庭 这房子闹鬼 所以算是违约？
There could be a miracle comeback.
说不定能奇迹逆转
Subtitle translation by: Aya Kudo
字幕翻译：赤焰